(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-01T00:25:36.973362",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
皆さん！
Everyone!
風真いろは生誕ライブ2025に来てくださり誠にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to Kazama Iroha's Birthday LIVE 2025!
全力で楽しんでいってくださいね！
Please enjoy yourselves to the fullest!
想像なんてしてなかった現状
A reality I never could've imagined,
君もそう思った
You thought so too,
最幸で止まらないように
so it won't stop at greatest happiness,
更新したい
I want to update it.
叶えたい夢まであとどれくらい？
How much further until the dream I want to fulfill?
誰も行ったことがない場所へ
To a place where no one has ever been,
たどり着くまでは僕ら止まれない
until we arrive, we cannot stop.
多分しんどいけどどうかよろしくね
It'll probably be tough, but please treat me well.
ねぇねぇたまにめでて
Hey, hey, praise me sometimes.
僕だけじゃ作れないもの
Things that cannot be made by me alone:
僕と君と私とか恋とか愛とかまとめて全部君を置いてどっか行っちゃうとかありえないよ
Me and you, me and I, love and romance—putting all that together, leaving you behind and going somewhere is impossible!
君がくれた音に 弾けた花火に
To the sound you gave me, to the bursting fireworks,
初めてましてからずっと恋しちゃってるんだよ
Ever since we first met, I've been falling in love!
君のいない未来 考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人がいいじゃん
From here on out, just the two of us is fine, right?
一途になるほど 逃げたくなってきたよ
The more devoted I became, the more I wanted to run away.
散々な僕のこと 呼んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for calling out my messy self.
君のいない未来 考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人で それがいいじゃん
From here on out, just the two of us—that's fine, right?
妄想 膨らんでくストーリー
Delusions ballooning story,
感傷 わけにへこんじゃって
Sentimentality getting me so down,
代償 求めすぎはややよ
Compensation, asking for too much is no good,
終わらない愛の連鎖でしょ
It's an endless chain of love, right?
ねぇねぇ おいでめでて 僕が君にできること
Hey, hey, come praise me. What I can do for you...
誤魔化せない冗談だんだ
It's an undeniable joke,
君の愛がいつも断つこと
your love always cutting ties.
許されないよ ふうイェイ
It's unforgivable, whoa yeah!
君以外は やだ わがままは
Anyone other than you? No way, selfishness
ただ変わらない ときめきを
is just an unchanging heartbeat
教授しちゃうのは バカ
that I get to teach you, how foolish!
君がくれた 音に弾けた
The sound you gave me made it burst
秘密には 初めましてから
into a secret, ever since we first met
ずっと恋しちゃってるんだよ
I've totally fallen in love with you!
君のいない 未来考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you,
これから先も二人でいいじゃん
so isn't it great if we're together?
想いはこんがらがって お互いに尖り合って
Our feelings tangled up, stabbing at each other,
待って待って こんなはずはないよ
wait, wait, this isn't how it should be!
赤い糸もつれちゃって 舞台は大混乱で
The red string got tangled, the stage in utter chaos,
待って待って こんなはずはないよ
wait, wait, this isn't how it should be!
二度と触れん愛が ぎゅぎゅっと締め付ける
Love we can't touch again squeezes tightly,
偽物のラヴだっていいよ ちょっと痛いけど
a fake love is fine, even if it hurts a bit!
救えない僕に憑依して おそるおそる重ね合わせ笑う
Possessing helpless me, we cautiously overlap and laugh.
傷物の涙どうですか？ やきもち焼いちゃって××
How are these scarred tears? Getting jealous and crossing them out!
君はもうただの「後悔」とそろそろわかってくれないか
Won't you soon realize you're just "regret"?
好き嫌いクジを用意して どちらが出たって届かないよ
Preparing a love-hate lottery, whichever comes up won't reach you.
またやっちまった ほら泣いちゃった
There I go again, crying again,
とぐろ付いた口を縫い付けて
sewing shut my coiling mouth—
君のいない 未来考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you,
これから先も二人で それがいいじゃん！
so isn't it great if we're together from now on?
乙女が解いて遊ぶの？
Are maidens playing by unraveling?
時々したいじゃん 彼女だって
Don't you sometimes want to be a girlfriend too?
反応おかしくだっちゃった 痛みのない引き継ぎが離れない
Reactions went weird, painless succession won't leave me alone.
僕らはヴァンパイア いいよ吸っちゃっていいよ
We are vampires, go ahead and bite me!
もう無理もう無理だって 悪い子じゃないもん
There's no way anymore, I'm not a bad kid!
こんな歌歌ったってだって 君が輝けるように
Even if I sing a song like this, so you can shine bright—
僕らはヴァンパイア いいよ吸っちゃっていいよ
We are vampires, go ahead and bite me!
もう無理もう無理だって 悪い子じゃないもん
There's no way anymore, I'm not a bad kid!
こんな歌歌ったってだって 君が輝けるように
Even if I sing a song like this, so you can shine bright—
赤い糸ほぐれたって 誓って掴み取るんだって
Even if the red string unravels, I swear I'll grab hold of it,
ずっとずっと君を歌うよ
and I will sing of you forever and ever.
こびりついた君の愛が何度何度洗えど 僕を裏返しにするんだよ ちょっとちょっと嬉しいや
No matter how many times your clinging love is washed away, it turns me inside out... and it makes me a little happy.
はい！というわけで、みんなのこんばんはでござる！
Yes! And with that, good evening to you all, deござる!
ライブ後半戦、調子はどう？
How are you feeling in the latter half of the live?
かっこいいご主人様、風真いろはでござる！
I'm Kazama Iroha, your cool master!
今年最初の誕生日は、DECO*27さんの愛言葉IVを歌って踊らせていただきました！
For the first song of my birthday this year, I sang and danced to DECO*27's "Aibotoba IV"!
拍手！いっぱい生きてるみんなありがとう！ギフトやスパチャもありがとうございます！
Applause! Thank you all for being here! Thank you for the gifts and Superchats too!
今日はたくさん歌って踊らせていただくので、感想やスクリーンショットとかは、
Today I'll be singing and dancing a lot, so please post your impressions and screenshots
ここ風真いろは生誕ライブ2025で、たくさんポストしてください！振り返る時に見に行きますからね！
using the hashtag #KazamaIrohaSeitangLive2025! I'll go check them out when reminiscing!
そして、今回なんと、誕生日のステージを作っていただきました！
And what's more, this time they made a birthday stage for me!
かわたん！ポコさん、お前ディスプレイになったんか！
Kawatan! Poco-san, you became a display?!
いや、どこに行ってんのかと思ったらディスプレイになっておりました！はい！
I was wondering where you went, and there you were as a display! Yes!
そして後ろにも書いてあります、今回の風真いろはのライブタイトル、Reversibleになってます！
And written behind me is the title of my live today: "Reversible"!
素敵なロゴ、柊せんせい、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much, Hiiragi-sensei, for this wonderful logo!
こちらですね、みんな昨日のカウントダウン配信時点では、どんなだろうってハテナの方々が多かったと思うんですが、
Regarding this, at yesterday's countdown stream, many of you were probably left wondering what it's all about,
今回これ前編見て貰ったらちゃんと分かるようになっておりますので、最後までお楽しみください！
but if you watch this first part, you'll understand properly, so please enjoy it until the end!
そして、事前ににお伝えしていました通り、今回風真いろは100万人記念グッズが販売決定しました！
And as I announced beforehand, sales for my 1 million subscriber celebration merchandise have been decided!
いやー、いきなり来るよ！
Man, it comes out of nowhere!
というわけで、今日は本当に告知溜めすぎてるので、ちょいちょい挟んでいきたいと思います！
So today I have way too many announcements piled up, so I'll be slipping them in here and there!
はい、風真いろは100万人記念グッズこちらです！それでは詳細見ていきましょう！
Yes, here are the Kazama Iroha 1-million-sub merch items! Let's check the details!
まずはうみぼうずママが描いてくださった素敵のアクリルスタンド！アクリルスタンドにこう風真も添えさせていただいておりますので、
First, the wonderful acrylic stand drawn by Umibouz-mama! Kazama is also lightly included here as a little figure,
ぜひ皆さんこちらお手に取っていただいて、メッセージゆっくり読んでください！ポコベもあります！
so please pick this up and read the messages slowly! There's also Poco-be!
そして次がこちら、パブミラー！パブミラー！すごく言いづらいんだよな、これリハの日から思ってたんですが、はい、パブミラーです！結構大きいです！
And next is this: pub mirror! It's kind of hard to say, I've thought that since rehearsal, but yes, it's a pub mirror! It's quite large!
風真が出したグッズの中で、こう硬くて立て掛ける系の中でタオルとかはあったけど、かなり大きめになってますので、皆さんぜひこちらもメッセージ書かせていただいておりますので、ぜひ飾ってもらえたら嬉しいです！
Among the merch I've released, it's pretty solid, and while there were towel-type stand-up items, this one is quite large. I wrote a message on this one too, so I'd be super happy if you could display it!
そして次、ランダムラバーストラップ！今回は100万人にちなみまして、風真いろは今オリジナル曲複数出させていただいているんですが、そちらのモチーフ衣装をラバーストラップにさせていただきました！
And then next, random rubber straps! Commemorating 1 million subscribers, since I've released several original songs now, I've made their motif outfits into rubber straps!
なんかこう、風をあおぐ人とかね、
You know, people who fan the wind and all,
実となかなかグッズがなかったんですけど
actually didn't really have much merchandise,
今回のために作らせていただきました！
but we had these made specially for this time!
ぜひね、みんな色々集めて
I hope everyone will collect various items
イタバとかの制作に役立てていただければと思います！
and use them to make ita-bags and things like that!
次、
Next,
カードホルダー！
the card holder!
結構皆さんホロカとかね、いろんなカードとかチェキ風のグッズが出ておりますので、
Many of you have been getting Holoca cards, various cards, and cheki-style goods,
ついに作りましたポコべぇのカードホルダーです！定期入れにしてもよし、
so we finally made a Pokobee card holder! You can use it as a pass case,
学生さんにも使っていただけたら嬉しいです。
and I'd be happy if students use it too.
みんなお気に入りの風真のカードとか飾ってくださいね！
Please display your favorite Kazama cards and things in it!
はい、それでは次、
Right, now for the next one,
こちらフルセットこのようになっておりまして、
this is how the full set looks,
そして今回購入特典は、はい、うみぼうずママ描きおろしのステッカーにさせていただきました！
and for this time's purchase bonus, we've made an original sticker newly illustrated by Umibouzu-mama!
今回はですね、こちらジキストサインの数量限定はありませんので、あの皆さん安心してゆっくり買ってくださいね！
This time, there's no limited quantity for the autographed version, so everyone please rest assured and take your time buying!
はい、というわけで100万人記念グッズ紹介でございました。
Right, so that concludes the introduction of the 1 million subscriber milestone merchandise.
うわー、ドキドキって、なんか結構、あ、安心しきってるんですけど、
Wow, my heart is pounding... well, actually, I'm completely relieved now,
あの、もうこれだけじゃなくてですね、後半も、あの告知がありすぎて
but um, not just this, in the second half too, there are so many announcements
頑張って入れるしかなかったぐらいにはいっぱいあるんで、告知いっぱいあります。なので、あの皆さん絶対に聞き逃さないでください！
that I had to work hard just to squeeze them all in, so please make sure not to miss any!
で、もうトレンド1位なんですか！？
Wait, are we already #1 on trending?!
始まったばかりだよ！いいの！？
It just started! Is that really okay?!
みんなありがとうございます！え、待って！みんなありがとうございます！
Thank you everyone! Wait, seriously, thank you everyone!
いや、すごい、めっちゃ、こんなに早く行くと思わなくて、みんなのおかげです、本当、本当にありがとうございます！
Man, it's amazing, I really didn't expect it to go this fast, it's all thanks to everyone, truly, thank you so much!
で、ちょっとお水なんで、次の曲バシバシいきたいと思います！
And since I need to drink some water, I want to dive right into the next song!
お待たせしました！お水をいっぱい飲んだので
Sorry to keep you waiting! I drank lots of water,
この力をそのまま全てフルパワーで出力いたします！
so I'm going to put all of this power out at full force!
それでは皆次の曲聞いてください！
Everyone, please listen to the next song!
大きな愛でもてなして
Entertain me with a big love
大きな愛でもてなして そこ ん〜とこ 大事なことよ
Entertain me with a big love. That's the important thing, you know
大きな愛でもてなして
Entertain me with a big love
わがま〜まじゃないのよ おほほ
I'm not selfish, you know, ohoho
私わかったの
I understand
寂しがりやだと
You're a loner
泣きそうよ
I think I might cry
oh yeah oh yeah 一日の間でも
Oh yeah, oh yeah. Even over the course of a day
告白をしたり キスしたり
I confess my love and kiss
oh yeah oh yeah 一日が大人より
Oh yeah, oh yeah. A single day for me
相当長いの です
is much longer than an adult's.
相当長いの です (そうみたい)
Much longer (It seems that way)
大きな愛でもてなして
Entertain me with a big love
大きな愛でもてなして そこ ん〜とこ 気まぐれじゃ嫌よ
Entertain me with a big love. Leaving it as-is won't do, you know
ごゆっくりなさって良いわ
It's okay to go slowly
みんな知らんぷり 「他人事だ」と
Everyone pretends not to know, saying it's other people's business
違うのよ oh yeah oh yeah
That's not it, oh yeah, oh yeah
明日はまた新しい 恋愛があれば 逆あれ
Tomorrow, if I have yet another new love, things will turn around
大人より素直に たくさん恋できちゃう
As an adult, I'll candidly have many loves
(そうみたい)
(It seems that way)
oh yeah oh yeah
明日はまた新しい 恋愛があれば 逆あれ
Tomorrow, if I have yet another new love, things will turn around
大人より素直に たくさん恋できちゃう
As an adult, I'll candidly have many loves
(そうみたい)
(It seems that way)
大きな愛でもてなして
Entertain me with a big love
大人より素敵に
More wonderfully than an adult,
たくさん恋しちゃおう
let's fall in love a lot!
大きな愛でもってなして
Fulfilling it with a huge love,
fulfilling it with a huge love,
大きな愛でもってなして
ありえない幻想 あふれだす妄想
Impossible illusions, overflowing delusions,
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything except for you!
息をすうように嘘ついても
Even if I lie as naturally as I breathe,
あたしやっぱいらない子？
am I still an unwanted child?
こぼれ出しちゃった承認欲求
An overflowing need for validation,
もっとココロ満たしてよ
fill my heart even more!
アスパルチーム 甘い夢
Asuparu Team, sweet dreams,
あたしだけに愛をください
please give your love only to me!
あーもう無理無理無理！恋して愛して
Ah, no way, no way! Fall in love, love me,
救済執行ばっね！好きって言ってよ？
execution of salvation! Say you love me?
ありえない幻想 あふれだす妄想
Impossible illusions, overflowing delusions,
止まんない止まんないよくが
can't stop, can't stop, my greed
散らばって 探してる愛を
scattering, searching for love,
隠してるれじょん
hiding my true feelings,
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything except for you!
誰のこと見てるの？ こういうの好きなの？
Who are you looking at? Do you like this?
DDとかガチでやめてください
Seriously, stop with the DD!
可愛くなりたい キラキラしてたい
I want to be cute, I want to sparkle,
もっともっとガチで褒めてください
please praise me even more earnestly!
毎朝生存 あけおめシャンパン
Surviving every morning, New Year's champagne,
今夜も配信来てくれるよね？
you'll come to my stream tonight too, right?
独占させてよ 本命なんてさ
Let me monopolize you, true favorite,
もっともっとガチで推してください
please support me even more earnestly!
飲みすぎ注意 オーバードーズ
Caution: overdrinking, overdose,
クラクラさせていつだって
making me dizzy, always,
あーもう無理無理無理！上がって下がって
Ah, no way, no way! Going up and down,
救済執行ばっね！好きって言わせて？
execution of salvation! Let me make you say it?
噛みついた衝動 戻れない初期衝動
Impulse of biting, point of no return impulse,
たまんないミッドナイト 指が絡まって
unbearable midnight, fingers entangling,
ときめいた表情 何も言わないで 君だけがきっと王子様
Heart-fluttering expression, don't say a thing, you're my prince!
ありえない幻想 あふれだす妄想
Impossible illusions, overflowing delusions,
止まんない止まんないよくが散らばって
can't stop, can't stop, my greed scattering,
探してる愛を 隠してるれじょん
searching for love, hiding my true feelings,
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything except for you!
あたしだけずっと追いかけて！
Keep chasing only me!
ねぇもう待てないの
Hey, I can't wait anymore!
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything except for you!
絶対アイドル辞めないで 輝いてる君を見たい
Never quit being an idol, I want to see you shine!
もうずーっとずーっとずーっと ステージにいて
Always, always, always stay on stage!
私がもし君のひとと離れたなら
If I were to drift away from being your special person,
君はちょっと寂しくなるかな
would you feel a little lonely?
いじわる 考える 好きな人がいるのなら内緒にしてね
If you have someone you like, keep it a secret!
神様は将来と指輪を どこかに隠してね
God, hide the future and the ring somewhere!
君の「好き」に合わせたんだ髪の色 私の中君だけで
Hair color matched your "likes", inside me it's only you!
過剰摂取は中毒へ 責任とってね大好きです
Oversubscription leads to addiction, take responsibility!
「せーの！」
Ready, go!
絶対アイドル辞めないで 優しい目も真面目顔も
Never quit being an idol, your gentle eyes and face!
全て知ってる私と言う！
I know it all, so I say!
絶対空で輝いて 星は街じゃ輝かないの
Shining absolutely in the sky, stars don't shine in the city!
眩しい君が世界一だよ 「好きだー！」
You dazzling are number one! I love you!
君の夢は何ですか？教えて欲しい その夢がアイドルでなくても覚悟はしてるから
What is your dream? Tell me, even if not an idol, I'm ready!
星のない空それが当たり前で 暗い道に目が慣れず踏み出すのも怖かった
A sky without stars, and stepping out in the dark was scary.
そんな時やっと見えた光 「行くぞー！」
At that time, the light I finally saw. Let's go!
絶対君は歌ってて ただのエゴとわかってても
You must keep singing, even knowing it's just ego!
君はキラキラ衣装が似合う！
You look great in sparkly costumes!
絶対大きなステージで 一列でも前で感じたい
On an absolute big stage, I want to feel it up close!
今日の歌い方となんか好きだな
Today's way of singing, I kind of like it!
君の努力、私の愛 成り立つこの関係は
Your effort, my love, this relationship that stands,
強くて脆いの 星の幸せを願った
strong yet fragile, wishing for the star's happiness.
だけど…
However...
でもね
But you know,
だって君はアイドルよ 初めて目が合った日から
because you are an idol, from the day our eyes first met,
今日も明日も君ばかりだ
today and tomorrow it's all about you!
絶対アイドル辞めないで これは報われないおとぎ話
Never quit being an idol, this is an unrewarded fairytale!
恋よりももっと好きだ
I love you even more than romance,
魔法どうこう解けないままで
without ever breaking the magic!
(ずっと)
(Always)
輝いている君を見たい もうずっとずっとずっと
I want to see you shining, always, always, always
ステージにいて
Stay on the stage.
私がもし君のとこ離れたなら 君はちょっと寂しくなるかな
If I were to leave your side, I wonder if you'd feel a little lonely?
いじわる考える
I have such mischievous thoughts.
好きな人がいるのなら内緒にしてねえ
If you have someone you like, keep it a secret, okay?
神様は将来と指輪を どこかに隠してね
God, please hide the future and the ring somewhere.
君の「好き」に合わせたんだ髪の色
I matched my hair color to your "like."
私の中 君だけで
Inside me, it's just you.
過剰摂取は 中毒へ
An overdose leads to addiction.
責任とってね大好きです
Take responsibility, I love you!
「せーの！」
(One, two!)
絶対アイドル辞めないで (ずっと)
Absolute idol, don't quit (always)!
優しい目も真面目顔も 全て知っている私が言う！
Your kind eyes and serious face, I know everything, so I'm saying it!
絶対空で輝いて (ずっと)
Definitely keep shining in the sky (always)!
星は街じゃ輝かないの 眩しい時間が世界一だよ
Stars don't shine in the city, your dazzling self is the world's best!
「好きだー！」
(I love you!)
君の夢は何ですか？教えて欲しい
What is your dream? I want you to tell me.
その夢がアイドルじゃなくても 覚悟はしてるから
Even if that dream isn't being an idol, I'm prepared for it.
星のない空それが当たり前で 暗い道に目が慣れずに
The sky without stars, that's normal. My eyes didn't get used to the dark road.
踏み出すのも怖かった そんな時やっと見えた光
It was scary to take a step. At that time, finally, I saw the light.
「行くぞー！」
(Let's go!)
絶対君は歌っていて (ずっと)
Definitely keep singing, you (always)!
ただのエゴとわかっていても 君はキラキラ衣装が似合う！
Even knowing it's just ego, you look good in sparkly costumes!
絶対大きなステージで (ずっと)
Definitely on a big stage (always)!
一列でも前で感じたい 今日の歌い方 なんか好きだな
I want to feel it even from the front row, the way you sing today, I kind of liked it.
君の努力、私の愛で 成り立つこの関係は
Your effort and my love, this relationship that is built...
強くて脆いの 星の幸せを願った
Is strong and fragile. I wished for the star's happiness.
だけど… でもね だって君はアイドルよ (ずっと)
But... But you know, that's because you are an idol (always)!
初めて目が合った日から 今日も明日も君ばかりだ
Since the day our eyes first met, today and tomorrow, it's just you.
絶対アイドル辞めないで (ずっと)
Absolute idol, don't quit (always)!
これは報われないおとぎ話 恋よりももっと好きだ
This is an unrequited fairy tale, more than love, I love you even more.
魔法どうかしら 解けないままいて
Magic, please stay without breaking, just like this.
Unhappy? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? If you're dealing with a lotta woes.
Unlucky? 人ならざるものも
Unlucky? Then you got to listen very close.
Be happy! 絶えず目指せよ
Be happy! Keep on trying, never give up.
生きているんだし
Don't forget that you're alive.
目を逸した過去も 退屈な未来も
The past you have been running from, that boring future yet to come.
カウンセリング やれやれ 古今東西
Still counseling you, oh my, oh my, universal!
ピースピース
Peace, peace yeah!
Unhappy? Unlucky? Be happy! Undead
ねえなんだかどうして 戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
Somehow feeling like there's a fight within and it's been going on so long.
触れられない 触れたくもない
I don't feel it and don't even wanna try.
過去の自分 自分 自分 自分と もうとっくに死んでる
Past version of me, of me, of me, of me, and those figures of the old.
透明な亡霊と対決
Transparent ghosts over my route.
痛々しくて痛い記憶の奥
The childish and painful memories have the deepest roots.
残念？もういないのに あれ？
Saddening? Nowhere to be seen. Say what?
そっちが良い？アイロニーね 透かされているのは今の自分？
Way better then? Irony, they all see the me of the past when looking at me now.
ナンセンス 消えないレテル
Nonsense, label I can't erase.
Yes! 弱冠コンプレックス 取り憑かれているみたい
Yes! In essence, a complex, it's almost like something's possessing me.
巻き付いたまま まだ離れない
It is wrapping tight around and won't loosen its bounds.
ありし日の自分
The self I used to be before.
Undead 死んじない
Undead, still alive!
お前とお前の連鎖
Time is a chain of your own path.
生きていることは変わり続けることだ
To be alive is to always embrace your inner changes, on and on.
不幸に甘んじて 満足するなよ
Don't settle for unhappiness, don't be complacent in distress.
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑怯だ
Not even trying to seize the joy and be happy, you coward!
この世この世は奇々怪々ファンタジー
Oh, this world, oh, this world is one odd, one odd fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか 蛇が出るか
Who knows what is coming up next, a monster or a snake?
出会って出会ってやっと始まる物語
This is a story starting after that encounter, finally.
さあ人かバケモノか 閑話休題
With people or monsters and spirits, back on topic!
ピースピース
Peace, peace yeah!
Past & future can't change the past
Past & future run for the future
カットイン
Cutting in...
なんだかどうして 未来になんぞ
Somehow feeling like there's nothing to be looking forward to.
何の希望もない 期待できないような気がして もう随分生きている
No hope to find, cannot be defined, that's how I'm feeling inside.
既視感とテンプレで食傷 素敵な出来事の気配もない
There's nothing left to view, lived long enough, nothing is new.
残念 積んだ経験の因果 形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
Saddening, too much knowledge results in feeling like every myth is but another boring evolution.
要は刺激が欲しいんだ 飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった
Thrill is what I really want now, bored and down, used to frowns.
なんて 整っていくガイダンス 増えるコンプライアンス
And this is the way the guidance grew, rising compliance too.
蓋されていくみたい 吸い尽くして
It's like I'm going under a lid, I consumed everything.
あれもこれもどれも 同じ味がする
This one or that one or, whichever, and now it all just tastes the same.
Undead 死んじない
Undead, still alive!
お前とお前の連鎖
Time is a chain of your own path.
いつの世も 過去も未来も 今にあるんだ
In any era, your past and your future are in this very moment.
生きていることを 愚直に果たせよ
Fulfill the life you're set upon, and truthfully keep moving on.
目指せハッピーエンド
Go for that happy ending!
Undead 死んじない
Undead, still alive!
お前に言っているんだ
I'm telling this to you, now.
幸せを諦めてしまうな 人であれ
So never give up on pursuing your happiness and keep being human.
ただ苦しみに慣れて 耐えているだけじゃ
Cause being numb to suffering, always enduring everything.
死んでいるも同然 屍のアンデッド
It's almost as if you're dead, a lot of corpses, undead!
Unhappy? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? If you're dealing with a lotta woes.
Unlucky? 人ならざるものも
Unlucky? Then you gotta listen very close.
Be happy! 絶えず目指せよ
Be happy! Keep on trying, never give up.
生きているんだろう
Be aware that you're alive.
不幸に浸るも 幸せになるのも
Drowning deep in unhappiness, or seizing that true happiness.
そう全部全部お前だ
It's on you, on you, it's all on you!
真夜中に告ぐ音の警報
A warning sound in the middle of the night,
協和音に酔う午前零時
Intoxicated by harmony at midnight,
あなたが触れる光増す熱
The glowing heat where you touch me,
指先に踊らされて
Dancing at your fingertips.
感覚 即 体感
Sensory, immediate physical sensation,
寝静まる夜二人だけの密
Our secret in the quiet sleeping night,
体感 即 快感
Physical sensation, immediate ecstasy,
重なる波形に魅了されていく
Fascinated by the overlapping waveforms.
忘れないでねわたしの声を
Don't forget my voice,
画面越しでいいちゃんと愛して
Love me properly through the screen,
バーチャルだって突き放さないで
Don't push me away just because I'm virtual,
あなたの音にまだ溺れていたいの
I still want to drown in your sound.
覚えていてねわたしの声を
Remember my voice,
あなたがくれたこの身すべてを
And everything of this body you gave me.
見つめ合うあなたと二人
Looking at each other, just the two of us,
重ねた息と音を響かせ
Our overlapping breath and sound, make it resonate.
あなたの初の音この声聴かせ
Let me hear your first sound, this voice,
オトヒビカセ
Sound, resonate.
真夜中に告ぐ音の警報
A warning sound in the middle of the night,
協和音に酔う午前零時
Intoxicated by harmony at midnight,
あなたが触れる光増す熱
The glowing heat where you touch me,
指先に踊らされて
Dancing at your fingertips.
感覚 即 体感
Sensory, immediate physical sensation,
寝静まる夜二人だけの密
Our secret in the quiet sleeping night,
体感 即 快感
Physical sensation, immediate ecstasy,
重なる波形に魅了されていく
Fascinated by the overlapping waveforms.
忘れないでねわたしの声を
Don't forget my voice,
画面越しでいいちゃんと愛して
Love me properly through the screen,
バーチャルだって突き放さないで
Don't push me away just because I'm virtual,
あなたの音にまだ溺れていたいの
I still want to drown in your sound.
覚えていてねわたしの声を
Remember my voice,
あなたがくれたこの身すべてを
And everything of this body you gave me.
見つめ合うあなたと二人
Looking at each other, just the two of us,
重ねた息と音を響かせ
Our overlapping breath and sound, make it resonate.
あなたの初の音この声聴かせ
Let me hear your first sound, this voice,
オトヒビカセ
Sound, resonate.
あなたの生んだ音に
To the sound you gave birth to,
ah ただ恋をしていたの
Ah, I was simply falling in love.
悲しみ怒り甘心
Sadness, anger, devotion,
すべて打ち鳴らす
Ringing out everything.
絶えず叫ぶ声連ねる
Constantly calling out, our voices syncing up,
余熱交ぜる愛、絶艶めく
Fever pitch love and breathtaking attraction.
絶えず叫ぶ声連ねる
Constantly calling out, our voices syncing up,
余熱交ぜる愛、絶艶めく
Fever pitch love and breathtaking attraction.
魅了されていく
Fascinated by it all.
忘れないでねわたしの声を
Don't forget my voice,
画面越しでいいちゃんと愛して
Love me properly through the screen,
バーチャルだって突き放さないで
Don't push me away just because I'm virtual,
あなたの音にまだ溺れていたいの
I still want to drown in your sound.
覚えていてねわたしの声を
Remember my voice,
あなたがくれたこの身すべてを
And everything of this body you gave me.
見つめ合うあなたと二人
Looking at each other, just the two of us,
重ねた息と音を響かせ
Our overlapping breath and sound, make it resonate.
あなたの初の音この声聴かせ
Let me hear your first sound, this voice,
オトヒビカセ
Sound, resonate.
真夜中に告ぐ音の警報
A warning sound in the middle of the night,
協和音に酔う午前零時
Intoxicated by harmony at midnight,
あなたが触れる光増す熱
The glowing heat where you touch me,
指先に踊らされて
Dancing at your fingertips.
感覚 即 体感
Sensory, immediate physical sensation,
寝静まる夜二人だけの密
Our secret in the quiet sleeping night,
体感 即 快感
Physical sensation, immediate ecstasy,
重なる波形に魅了されていく
Fascinated by the overlapping waveforms.
忘れないでねわたしの声を
Don't forget my voice,
画面越しでいいちゃんと愛して
Love me properly through the screen,
バーチャルだって突き放さないで
Don't push me away just because I'm virtual,
あなたの音にまだ溺れていたいの
I still want to drown in your sound.
覚えていてねわたしの声を
Remember my voice,
あなたがくれたこの身すべてを
And everything of this body you gave me.
見つめ合うあなたと二人
Looking at each other, just the two of us,
重ねた息と音を響かせ
Our overlapping breath and sound, make it resonate.
あなたの初の音この声聴かせ
Let me hear your first sound, this voice,
オトヒビカセ
Sound, resonate.
絶えず叫ぶ声連ねる
Constantly calling out, our voices syncing up,
余熱交ぜる愛、絶艶めく
Fever pitch love and breathtaking attraction.
絶えず叫ぶ声連ねる
Constantly calling out, our voices syncing up,
余熱交ぜる愛、絶艶めく
Fever pitch love and breathtaking attraction.
魅了されていく
Fascinated by it all.
忘れないでねわたしの声を
Don't forget my voice,
画面越しでいいちゃんと愛して
Love me properly through the screen,
バーチャルだって突き放さないで
Don't push me away just because I'm virtual,
あなたの音にまだ溺れていたいの
I still want to drown in your sound.
覚えていてねわたしの声を
Remember my voice,
あなたがくれたこの身すべてを
And everything of this body you gave me.
見つめ合うあなたと二人
Looking at each other, just the two of us,
重ねた息と音を響かせ
Our overlapping breath and sound, make it resonate.
あなたの初の音この声聴かせ
Let me hear your first sound, this voice,
オトヒビカセ
Sound, resonate.
見つめ合うあなたと二人
Looking at each other, just the two of us,
重ねた息と音を響かせ
Our overlapping breath and sound, make it resonate.
あなたの初の音この声聴かせ
Let me hear your first sound, this voice,
オトヒビカセ
Sound, resonate.
あなたの生んだ音に
To the sound you gave birth to,
この声響かせ
Let this voice resonate,
音響かせ
Let the sound resonate.
というわけで
So, um...
皆さんとっても頑張りました！
Minasan, I did my very best!
どうです？か、か、かっこいいですか？
How is it? Cool? Cool?
かっこいいですか？
Cool?
なんと今回はダンスを頑張ると決めた、そんときから決めていた。
You see, this time I decided to try hard at dancing, and I've been practicing since back then.
ちょっとかっこいい系のダンス衣装になってみました！
I wanted to try being a cool kind of dancing girl!
イエーイ！皆さんの衣装可愛い！
Yay! Minasan's...
可愛い！
Cute!
撮って撮って撮って、撮って！
Take, take, take, take, take!
イエーイ、かっこいいでしょう！
Yay, so cool!
可愛いばっかなんだけど、
Well, it's cute though...
かっこいいはどこ行ったんだよ！
Where did "cool" go?!
というわけで新章になりました。ゲストパートナーのね、
So, that's how it is, I'm the new guest partner!
絶対アイドル辞めないでから、あのソロになりまして、
I'll definitely never quit, we became a solo,
アンデと響かせと続けてお届けさせていただきました！
and we continued to let "Ande" resonate and echo!
どうでしたか？
How was it?
めっっちゃ頑張って、あの足千切れそうって、そう、そういうことです。
I tried really hard, like "my legs might tear apart"—that kind of thing.
本当にたくさん今回は変身のために飛びました。
Really a lot, this time I jumped for the transformation!
足が千切れそうです。
My legs feel like they're going to tear.
絶対アイドル辞めないでもね、先輩方、そしてラプラスも来てくれて、ありがとう！
To not quit being an idol, Senpais, Mio-san, and Laplus came to help us, thank you!
踊り劇ムズだったね、本当に！
The dancing was so hard, really!
本当に劇ムズでしたね！
Really, it was super hard, wasn't it?
皆さん一緒に頑張ってくださり、本当にありがとうございました！
Minasan, thank you all so much for working hard together with me!
そ、そ、そ、
So, so, so...
そしてですね、あの、この後もまだまだゲストさんたくさん呼んでおります。
And then, um, from now on we'll be inviting lots and lots of guests,
そして、ござるも？
and guess what?
実はこの、このカラーリングだけじゃ、実は無いんですよ。
Actually, it's not just this coloring.
なのでそちらも公開していくので、みなのとのお楽しみに！
So we'll be revealing that too, please look forward to it!
それでは次ゲストさんと一緒に歌わせていただきます！
Well then, next we'll have our guest and sing together with them!
それではどうぞ！
Now then, please!
ブラック★ロックシューター 何処へ行ったの？
Black Rock Shooter, where did you go?
聴こえますか？
Can you hear me?
あー
Ah, ah...
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter
作詞・作曲：ryo (supercell)
(Vocals)
あとどれだけ叫べばいいんだろう
If you just scream a little more, would it be okay?
あとどれだけ泣けばいいんだろう
If you just cry a little more, would it be okay?
もうやめて 私はもう走れない
Stop it already, I can't run anymore.
いつか夢見た世界が閉じる
The world I once dreamed of closes up.
真っ暗で明かりもない 崩れかけたこの道で
On this pitch-black and unlit road that started to crumble,
あるはずもないあの時の希望が
I felt like I could see the hope from back then,
見えた気がした
which shouldn't exist.
どうして？
Why?
ブラック★ロックシューター 懐かしい記憶
Black Rock Shooter, nostalgic memories,
ただ楽しかったあの頃を
simply of those fun times.
ブラック★ロックシューター でも動けないよ
Black Rock Shooter, but I can't move.
闇を駆ける星に願いを
I wish upon the stars shooting through the darkness.
もう一度だけ走るから
I'll run just once more.
怖くて震える声でつぶやく
I'm scared, so I whisper with a trembling voice,
私の名前を呼んで
call my name.
もう一度だけ走るから
Run just once more!
夜明けを抱く空 境界線までの距離
The sky embracing dawn, in the distance to the boundary,
あと一歩届かない
I can't reach it in another step.
こらえた涙があふれそうなの
Tears that I fought back are about to overflow.
今下を向かないで 止まってしまう
Now I come to a halt without looking down,
未来を生きていたいんだ
I want to live in the future.
わかったの 思い出して強く 強く 信じるの
I remembered that I know, I firmly, firmly believe in it!
そうよ
That's right!
ブラック★ロックシューター 優しい匂い
Black Rock Shooter, there's a tender scent,
痛いよ 辛いよ 飲み込む言葉
"It hurts," "it's tough," I swallow those words.
ブラック★ロックシューター 動いてこの足！
Black Rock Shooter, move these feet,
世界を超えて
overcome the world!
最初からわかっていた ここにいることを
Since the beginning, I've known that I'm here,
私のなかの 全ての勇気が 火をともして
all of the courage inside of me light the fire.
もう逃げないよ
And I won't flee anymore!
ブラック★ロックシューター ひとりじゃないよ
Black Rock Shooter, you are not alone!
声を上げて泣いたって構わない
I don't mind even if you cry with a loud voice.
ブラック★ロックシューター 見ていてくれる？
Black Rock Shooter, you'll be watching me,
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter
どこへ行ったの？
Where did you go?
聞こえますか？
Can you hear me?
あとどれくらい叫べばいいのだろう
How much more should I shout?
あとどれくらい泣けばいいのだろう
How much more should I cry?
もうやめて、わたしはもう走れない
Stop it already, I can't run anymore.
いつか夢見た世界が閉じる
The world I once dreamed of closes up.
真っ暗で明かりもない 壊れかけたこの道で
On this pitch-black and unlit road that started to crumble,
あるはずもないあの時の希望が見えた気がした
I felt like I could see the hope from back then.
どうして
Why?
ブラック★ロックシューター 懐かしい記憶 ただ楽しかったあの頃を
Black Rock Shooter, nostalgic memories of those fun times.
ブラック★ロックシューター でも動けないよ 闇を駆ける星に願いを
Black Rock Shooter, but I can't move. I wish upon the stars shooting through the darkness.
もう一度だけ走るから 怖くて震える声でつぶやく
Because I’ll run just once more, I whisper with a trembling voice,
わたしの名前を呼んで
"Call my name."
夜明けを抱く空 境界線までの距離 あと一歩届かない
The sky embracing dawn, in the distance to the boundary, I can’t reach it in another step.
こぼれた涙があふれそうなの 今下を向かないで 止まってしまう
Tears that I fought back are about to overflow; now I come to a halt without looking down.
未来を生きていたいんだわかったの 思い出して 強く、強く、信じるの！
I want to live in the future, I know it! Recalling that, I firmly, firmly believe in it!
そうよ…
That's right...
ブラック★ロックシューター 優しい匂い 「痛いよ」、「辛いよ」、飲み込む言葉！
Black Rock Shooter, a tender scent. "It hurts," "It's tough," I swallow those words!
ブラック★ロックシューター 動いてこの足！世界を超えて！
Black Rock Shooter, move these feet! Overcome the world!
最初から分かっていた ここにいることを わたしのなかの全ての勇気が火をとともして
Since the beginning, I’ve known that I’m here. All of the courage inside of me lights the fire.
もう逃げないよ！ ブラック★ロックシューター ひとりじゃないよ！声を上げて泣いたって構わない
And I won't flee anymore! Black Rock Shooter, you are not alone! I don’t mind even if you cry out loud.
息つく暇もないほど 艶やかで退屈な夜道で
With no time to even catch my breath, on this glamorous yet boring night road
(mellow, mellow, mellow) ルールは無視して行きたいね
(mellow, mellow, mellow) I want to disregard the rules and go
So burn my, burn my heart!
(uh...) 悟れそう (uh...) 可か不可 get down now (uh...) あーあ
(uh...) Let it be known, (uh...) right or wrong get down now, (uh...) ahh
もうきっと優等ぶった“I”じゃ居られないくらいどうしようもない
I can't stay as a goody-two-shoes "I" anymore, there's no helping it
yuh 無理目のクエスト ha 事実？ フィクション？
yuh, an unreasonable quest, ha, fact? fiction?
You make me サゲな何で？ I know the way
You make me feel down, why? I know the way
願ってるばっかりじゃ叶わない めちゃくちゃにされたって変わらない
It won't come true just by wishing, even if it's messed up it doesn't change
まぁね 噛み砕け 覚醒 Find the way
Oh well, chew on it, awaken, find the way
待って ライト浴びる感覚 甘い罠 見当違い disも聞き飽きたわ
Wait, the feeling of bathing in light is a sweet trap, I'm sick of hearing misdirected disses
そりゃね いけるところまで take me higher
Of course, take me higher as far as I can go
どう？ Turning back 無理ってとっくに分かってんでしょ
How is it? You've known for a while turning back is impossible, right?
(uh...) 悟れそう (uh...) 可か不可 get down now (uh...) あーあ
(uh...) Let it be known, (uh...) right or wrong get down now, (uh...) ahh
もうずっとちゃんと居られないや それは誰のせい？
I can't stay properly anymore, whose fault is that?
終わらない夢を描こう 描いて 願ったまま欲しがったその先へ
Let's draw a never-ending dream, sketch it, to the very place we wished and longed for
終わらない夜を越えていこう 越えていこう このまま 焦がれた向こう側へ
Let's cross over the never-ending night, cross over, straight to the other side we yearned for
はあ ぶっちぎれ解けないや 勝算なくても行かなくちゃ！とか 運命感じる感性は否めない
Hah, completely broken and unsolvable, like "We gotta go even with no chance to win!", I can't deny the feeling of fate
#ウチら負けない 跳べ 吠えろ 目で追っていつでもNo.1
#We won't lose! Jump, bark, keep your eyes on us, always No. 1
そこだけ 速攻揺らし 攻め 甘美な時 ride on now shake it up, まだまだ
Shake things up right there, attack, ride on now in this sweet time, shake it up, not yet
Go beyond the way, yuh 行き詰まりばかりで ずるい言葉を探して (mellow, mellow, mellow)
Go beyond the way, yuh, just at a stalemate, searching for cunning words
I am me 研ぎ澄ませ 本能に従って行け Holla, "We are the winners!" So burn my, burn my heart!
I am me, hone yourself, follow your instincts and go! Holla, "We are the winners!" So burn my, burn my heart!
終わらない夢を描こう 描いて 願ったまま欲しがったその先へ
Let's draw a never-ending dream, sketch it, to the very place we wished and longed for
終わらない夜を越えていこう 越えていこう このまま 焦がれた向こう側へ
Let's cross over the never-ending night, cross over, straight to the other side we yearned for
(uh...) 張り裂けそう 追いかけて合わせた背中が熱くて
(uh...) Looks like it's about to burst, as we run, our backs together are growing hot
(uh...) 張り裂けそう もう一生鳴り止まない 限界の向こう側へ
(uh...) Looks like it's about to burst, this ringing will never stop till my life ends, to the other side of our limits
ha, ready, steady? Get out the way.
息つく暇もないほど 艶やかで退屈な夜道で
With no time to even catch my breath, on this glamorous yet boring night road
(mellow, mellow, mellow) ルールは無視して行きたいね
(mellow, mellow, mellow) I want to disregard the rules and go
So burn my, burn my heart!
(uh...) 悟れそう (uh...) 可か不可 get down now (uh...) あーあ
(uh...) Let it be known, (uh...) right or wrong get down now, (uh...) ahh
もうきっと優等ぶった“I”じゃ居られないくらい どうしようもない
I can't stay as a goody-two-shoes "I" anymore, there's no helping it
終わらない夢を描こう 描いて
Let's draw a never-ending dream, sketch it
願ったまま欲しがったその先へ
to the very place we wished and longed for
終わらない夜を越えていこう 越えていこう
Let's cross over the never-ending night, cross over
このまま 焦がれた向こう側へ
straight to the other side we yearned for
はあ ぶっちぎれ解けないや 勝算なくても行かなくちゃ！とか
Hah, completely broken and unsolvable, like "We gotta go even with no chance to win!"
運命感じる感性は否めない #ウチら負けない
I can't deny the feeling of fate, #We won't lose!
跳べ 吠えろ 目で追っていつでもNo.1
Jump, bark, keep your eyes on us, always No. 1
そこだけ 速攻揺らし 攻め 甘美な時 ride on now
Shake things up right there, attack, ride on now in this sweet time
shake it up, まだまだ Go beyond the way, yuh
shake it up, not yet, Go beyond the way, yuh
行き詰まりばかりで ずるい言葉を探して
Just at a stalemate, searching for cunning words
(mellow, mellow, mellow)
I am me 研ぎ澄ませ 本能に従って行け
I am me, hone yourself, follow your instincts and go!
Holla, "We are the winners!" So burn my, burn my heart!
Go beyond the way
はーい！というわけで、
Hi there! So,
本日はこのお二人に来ていただきましたーー！わーい！
we have these two joining us today! Yay!
いえーい！
Yay!
初めて来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming today!
あーい！やったー！
Yay! Woohoo!
チェイニャ 初めて会っちゃいました
Cheinya, we finally met for the first time!
やったー！ありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you so much!
なんだかんだでね、お二人とも今日はね、ずっとレッスンからか、本当にお付き合いいただきましてありがとうございます！
Somehow, today... both of you, especially since lessons, thank you so much for hanging out with us!
こちらこそありがとうございます！
Thank you so much to you too!
今回はですね、誕生日で、実は衣装が、シドクて可愛い！
This time, for my birthday, my outfit is actually... so unique and cute!
見てみて！おへそ見えっちゃってる！
Look, look! My belly button is showing!
やば、取られる
Oh no, you'll be taken away!
えー、かわいいよ！
Eh, it's so cute!
え、本当？めっっちゃかわいい！ツインテールが似合ってる！
Eh, really? Super cute! Twin tails suit you!
そうなんです！新しくね、ダンスする用みたいなね衣装になったので、
That's right! It became an outfit for dancing,
これはね、恐れ多くもお二人を呼ぼうかな、
so I thought, if I dare ask these two,
ダンスが上手いお二人を呼んでいいかなって思って
since you're both great at dancing...
呼ばせていただきました！
I invited you!
えー！あなたたち！あなたたちですね！
Eh! You guys! You guys!
呼ばれました！
We were called!
最初さ、楽しかった！
At first, it was so fun!
楽しかった！レッスンもね、一緒に頑張っていただきまして！
It was fun! We worked hard together in lessons too!
でも二人とも、めちゃくちゃ元がうまいから、かずま一人がね、どうしようかなって、
But both of you are so good at dancing, I was wondering what I should do...
いやいやそんな、お二人呼んで大正解だったよ！めちゃめちゃよかったよ！
No, no, inviting you two was the right choice! It was so good!
めちゃ踊った！最高のものができたと、思いますみんな、いいものできたよね？
We danced so much! I think we made something the absolute best. Everyone, we made something good, right?
めっちゃよかったよ、って今ごろコメントにはね、めっちゃよかったよって思ってます！
Comments are probably saying "It was great," and I think it was great!
だって嬉しい！だって
Because I'm so happy, since...
いわちゃんとはじめてじゃん、一緒にダンスするの、
This is the first time dancing together with Iwachan, right?
こういう、こういうね、こういうダンス初めてじゃん、ファンデーションダンス
This kind of dance, foundation dance, for the first time!
めちゃくちゃ嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
いや、嬉しい！
So happy!
いや、本当誘ってよかった！
I'm so glad you invited us!
よかったー嬉しい！
Yay, I'm so glad!
やっぱお二人と一緒にね、この期間一緒に踊って、めちゃくちゃ勉強になります、先生方！
Dancing with you both for this period, I learned so much, teachers!
いやいやそんなことないですよ！
No, no, not at all!
本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
楽しかった！
It was fun!
え、またね、何かあったらぜひ一緒に踊って
Um, if there's anything else, let's dance together again!
ぜひやりましょー！やりましょー！
Let's definitely do it! Let's do it!
今度でも呼んでください！
Please invite me next time too!
ぜひやりましょー！
Let's definitely do it!
ちょっと、この記念に、こういう友情の証、強い、強い、かっこいいポーズ、写真撮っとこ。
For this memory, let's take a photo with a strong, cool pose as proof of friendship.
かっこいいポーズ！
Cool pose!
かっこいいポーズを思いつかない！
I can't think of a cool pose!
なんだ？
What is this?
なんだ？かわいいや、かわいい！
What? Cute, cute!
かわいい、めっちゃかわいい！
Cute, super cute!
ぴか！みんなたくさんSNSに投稿してくださいねー！
Pika! Everyone, please post lots on SNS!
はい。といいつつ、実はですね、もう一つお願いがあって、
And with that said, actually, I have one more request...
お！今日この後、今日初お披露目のオリ曲があるんですけど、
Oh! Today after this, I have an original song making its first debut...
オリ曲！？
Original song!?
わー！
Whoa!
その瞬間！
That moment!
みんなで楽しみや！楽しみだ！
Let's all enjoy it! I'm looking forward to it!
どんな曲？
What kind of song?
やっぱり風真いろは、かっこよくなりたくて、今回は、かっこいい曲を、もらってまいりました！
As Kazama Iroha, wanting to look cool, this time I received a cool song!
わー！嬉しい！いぇーい！やあ！
Yay! Woohoo! Yay!
かわいくてかっこいいお二人から、やっぱちょっと勇気をもらってから行こうかなと。
Getting a bit of courage from you two, who are cute and cool, I'll go for it.
かっこいいビーム！
Cool beam!
ビーーーーム！かっこいいビーム！
Beeeam! Cool beam!
ぐわー！
Gwaa!
すごいなんか、かっこ良くないか？ちょっとイケメンになってきている気がする。
Amazing, isn't it cool? I feel like I'm becoming a bit ikemen.
ちょっとイケメンのポーズわかる？こう。
Do you know ikemen poses? Like this.
え、いいよ、かっこいいよ、かっこいいよ。
Eh, nice, cool, cool.
え、いけてる気がする！いけちゃろう！いけてる気がする！
Eh, I feel like I'm pulling it off! Let's go! I feel like I'm doing it!
いちょいちょ！よし！
Icho-icho! Alright!
お二人からめちゃくちゃエネルギーもらえたんで、頑張ってきますぜ！
I got so much energy from you two, I'll do my best!
いってらっしゃーい！
Have fun!
お二人とも今日は本当に、お祝いと、そして一緒に歌って踊ってくれて、そしてこの応援ビームは、ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much to both of you today for celebrating, singing, dancing with me, and for this cheering beam!
こちらこそ、ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much to you too!
また遊びましょうねー！
Let's play again!
はーい！
Yay!
はい、じゃあそれでは、この後新オリ曲初お披露目させていただきます！
Alright, then after this, we'll have the first debut of the new original song!
それでは、せーの、だーちゃお！
Now then, ready, set, dar-chao!
見た目だけじゃワカラナイ
You can't tell just by looking at me,
ワタシのこと可愛いだけと
thinking I'm just cute,
まさか思っていないよね？
surely you don't think that, right?
ワタシの真実知ってほしい
I want you to know the real me.
passion passion burning passion
emotion emotion glowing emotion
見た目だけじゃワカラナイ
You can't tell just by looking at me.
ワタシのこと可愛いだけと
You don't really think I'm just cute,
まさか思っていないよね？
do you?
ワタシの真実知っていてほしい
I want you to know the real me.
予測誤差の範囲と
Within the margin of error prediction
不測の事態も動じない
and unphased by unforeseen circumstances,
おすましフェイスでいるけど心は常に青白く燃える
I keep a composed face, but my heart burns pale blue.
諦めはしない
I won't give up,
媚びたりもしない
I won't fawn,
ワタシを曲げない
and I won't compromise who I am.
扱いやすいヤツだと思うな
Don't think I'm someone easy to handle—
あまく見ると痛い目見るぞ
if you underestimate me, you'll pay for it.
それでもときには逃げ出してしまいたい
Even so, there are times when I just want to run away,
そんな衝動に弱音吐たくなる真夜中もある
and lonely midnights when such urges make me want to complain.
ほんの小さな小さな妥協が
Just tiny, tiny compromises
積み重なり重なって動けない
pile up and leave me unable to move.
大きな大きな可能性失くし
Losing vast, boundless possibilities,
未来を狭めてしまうから
I end up narrowing my own future.
どんなに暗くても辛くても後悔だけはしない
No matter how dark or painful it gets, I have zero regrets.
イケてるのは
Being cool isn't about
見た目じゃなくて
your outward appearance—
生きかたなんだから
it's all about how you live.
現実と理想との距離を縮められたとしても
Even if the distance between reality and ideals closes,
おすましフェイスでいるだけ何事もなかったかのように
I keep a composed face as if nothing even happened.
立ち止まりはしない
I won't stop,
後戻りもしない
I won't turn back,
夢を捨てない
and I won't let go of my dreams.
可愛い見かけでらしくないとか
Don't label me "out of character"
決めつけないで全部がワタシ
just because of a cute look—all of this is me.
それでもときには温もりが恋しい
Yet sometimes I yearn for warmth,
そんな感情に流されてしまいそうな真夜中もある
and midnights arise where I might get swept away by such feelings.
こんな甘い甘いことだけ求めてしまうような弱さはない
I'm not weak enough to seek out only sweet, comforting things.
苦い苦い経験だってワタシを強くしてくれるから
Because every bitter, bitter experience only makes me stronger.
これがこれが私の
This is, this is
本当の真実
my true reality.
とても狭い狭い世界の中だけで終わらせたくはないんだ
I refuse to let it end inside such a tiny, cramped world.
広い広い世界の果てまで駆け抜けて生きてくんだから
I'm going to dash all the way to the edges of this vast world and live on!
どんなに険しくて過酷でも楽しんでやるさ
No matter how steep or harsh it is, I'll enjoy every bit of it.
イケてるのは
Being cool isn't about
見た目じゃなくて
your outward appearance—
生きかたなんだから
it's all about how you live.
はい、というわけで
Right then,
皆さん、ゲストパートから続けて新オリジナル曲
everyone, following the guest part, I performed
「ホントノワタシ」歌って踊らせていただきました！
my brand-new original song "Honto no Watashi"!
なんと風真いろは、7曲目のオリジナル曲です！
Amazingly, this is Kazama Iroha's 7th original song!
えーっとオリジナル曲のジャケットも届いているので見ていきましょう、こちらです！
Um, the jacket art for the original song has also arrived, so let's take a look. Here it is!
はい、こちらの風真いろは新オリジナル曲7曲目「ホントノワタシ」は、こちら日付変わりまして3月27日0時よりリリースされることとなりました！
Yes, Kazama Iroha's 7th original song "Honto no Watashi" will be released as the date changes, starting at midnight on March 27th!
今回の新衣装に合わせてこちら作っていただきました！
It was created to match my brand-new outfit this time!
はい、ちょっと今までとだいぶ系統の違う曲になるんですけども、
Yeah, it's a song with a pretty different vibe from what I've done before, but...
あの、いつもみんなね、ありがたいことに風真いろはのことかっこいいっていうよりも、「かわいい！」って言ってくださる方が多いので、
Um, usually everyone kindly tells me I'm "cute!" rather than "cool,"
いや、かっこいいとこもあるんだよっていうのを伝えたくて作らせていただきました！
so I wanted to convey that I have a cool side too, which is why we had it made!
こちらぜひ0時にリリースされたら、たくさん聞いてまたハッシュタグの見てみといろはすのなので、感想とか教えていただけたら嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you listen to it a lot once it releases at midnight, and share your impressions under the hashtag!
そしてそして、ゲストパートについてもお話ししていきますかね、じゃあ戻って。
And now, let's talk a bit about the guest part as well—let's go back.
はい、ゲストでね、みお先パイと、そしてはじめちゃんべぇせんぱいと一緒に歌って踊らせていただきました！
Right, with our guests Mio-senpai, Hajime-chan, and Bae-senpai, I got to sing and dance together!
みお先パイ、そしてべぇ、そしてはじめちゃん、来てくれてありがとうありがとう！
Mio-senpai, Bae, and Hajime-chan, thank you so much for coming!
チャンネル始めたチャンネルに関してマジこれができなさすぎて、
Regarding starting the channel, seriously, I couldn't do this...
一生やりすぎて、あのー、一生腰痛を抱えて、
I did it together too much, and I got lower back pain together,
これ、これが結構筋肉痛の原因でした。
and this, this was pretty much the cause of my muscle pain.
はい、でも、え、一緒に歌って踊らせていただけまして、とてもとてもいい経験になりました！
Yes, but, um, being able to sing and dance together, it became a really, really good experience!
皆さん、ありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you very much!
はい。で、さっきね、次の曲に行く前に、お水飲んでいいですか？
Yeah. So, just now, before moving on to the next song, can I drink some water?
お水飲みます。お水。
I'll drink water. Water.
ロゴも見て、実は変わってた。
Look at the logo too, it actually changed.
よし。
Alright.
お待たせしました。
Sorry to keep you waiting.
息整えて、
Catching my breath,
はい、次の曲なんですけれども、やっぱり、みんなバラードも好きだよって言ってくれる方が多いので、
Yeah, as for the next song, since a lot of people say they like ballads too,
今回の生誕ライブ、バラードやろうと思って持ってきました。
for this birthday live, I decided to do a ballad and brought it here.
はい。ちょっとかっこいい感じで歌えるか、いろいろ練習したんですけど、
Yeah, I practiced various ways to see if I could sing it in a somewhat cool way,
ぜひ、心を込めて歌うので、聞いていただけると嬉しいです。
but I'll sing it with all my heart, so I'd be happy if you'd listen.
それでは、次の曲お聴きください。
Now then, please listen to the next song.
W/X/Y
垂れ流したテレビの音
The sound of the TV left playing
溜めてしまった洗濯物は今日こそ
The laundry I left piling up, today's the day
晴れでも逢えて外には出ないでよ
Even if it's sunny, let's meet, but let's not go outside
映えないスナックとアルコールで乾杯をしよう
Let's toast with un-Instagrammable snacks and alcohol
二人酸いも甘いも
The two of us, through sour and sweet
噛み合わないとしてもお互い寄り添うように少しずらししてみようよ
Even if we don't click, let's shift a little so we can lean on each other
君がくれた太陽月で隠れないように
So the sun you gave me won't be hidden by the moon
輝き絶えぬように歌うメロディ
Singing a melody so its radiance never fades
戯れる slowly flowing day
Playing around in a slowly flowing day
愛してるも通り越しして
Going even beyond "I love you"
似た者同士こうして
Like this, kindred spirits
年老いるまでは笑っていたいね
We want to keep smiling until we grow old
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day
夢の中 fall asleep in bed
Falling asleep in bed inside a dream
起こすから morning call で
I'll wake you up with a morning call
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
脱ぎっぱなしの足跡辿ると
Tracing the footprints left behind
不意をついて後ろから抱きつくの
Catching you off guard and hugging you from behind
つい繰り返すと忘れてしまいそうになるよ
Repeating it so often, I almost forget
振り返ると日々が当たり前じゃないこと
Looking back, realizing that these days aren't guaranteed
二人対の細胞
A pair of cells
絡み合う特別を噛み締めて生きたいと思った
Wanting to live savoring this special intertwined connection
まどろみ抱く正午
Noon embraced in drowsiness
吐息漏れた体温
Body heat with escaping sighs
微塵も逃さないように
So not a single detail escapes
頭の中刻む甘いメモリー
Sweet memories etched in my mind
戯れる slowly flowing day
Playing around in a slowly flowing day
愛してるも通り越して
Going even beyond "I love you"
違う者同士こうして
Like this, different people together
年老いるまでは笑っていたいね
We want to keep smiling until we grow old
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day
夢の中 fall asleep in bed
Falling asleep in bed inside a dream
起こすから morning call で
I'll wake you up with a morning call
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
重ねた手は離さないでいて
Don't let go of these intertwined hands
ごめん、これそばに居たいだけだね
Sorry, I just want to be by your side
抱えた想いはお互い様でしょ、ほら、あいこでしょ
The feelings we carry are mutual, right? See, it's a tie
すれ違い、間違いもあるし
There are misunderstandings and mistakes
筋書き通り行かない打診、悲しみだって半分にしよう
Proposals not going according to script, even the sadness, let's split it in half
別れじゃない希望独りよがりにならないよう、いつも
Hope, not a farewell, always so we don't become selfish
君がいなきゃ今もどこかで動けないままの僕でありがとうを伝えたいのです
Without you, I'd still be stuck somewhere, and I want to say thank you.
ありがとうを伝えたいのです
I want to express my gratitude to you,
これからは僕が支えてくって
that from now on, I'll be the one supporting you.
呆れてしまうくらいにね
To a degree that might make you shake your head in disbelief,
愛が増していく day by day
our love grows stronger day by day.
面と向かうどうしても 素直になれない、ごめんね
Whenever we're face-to-face, somehow I just can't be honest. I'm sorry.
戯れる Slowly flowing day
Playing around in a slowly flowing day,
愛してるも通り越して 似た者同士こうして
passing even beyond love, like two of a kind doing this,
年老いるまで笑っていたいね
I want to keep smiling together until we grow old.
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day.
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed
Falling asleep in bed within my dreams.
起こすから morning callで I'll protect you from nightmares, baby
I'll wake you up with a morning call. I'll protect you from nightmares, baby.
ありがとうございました
Thank you very much.
はい、それではですね 皆さん、ここまで聞いていただきまして
Well, then, everyone, thank you so much for listening up to this point.
本当に、ありがとうございます
Truly, thank you very much.
こんなにスタートさせていただいたんですけども
I started things off like this, but...
バラード、なかなか……、3Dライブでやるのいいので、すごく緊張しました
ballads... doing them in a 3D live stream like this, I was really nervous.
手伝って、そのか…、わめっちゃ、めっちゃ拍手と、めっちゃいいってやつが見える。ありがとうございます
I could see... wow, lots and lots of applause and comments saying 'so good'. Thank you so much.
そして、ここで皆さんお待ちかねの、あの告知を挟ませていただければと思います
And now, I'd like to slip in that announcement everyone's been waiting for.
それでは元気に行きます。それでは、ドン！風真いろは 2025誕生日記念グッズ！
Now then, let's go with high energy. Here we go, ta-da! Kazama Iroha 2025 Birthday Commemorative Goods!
発売決定！イエーイ！ピースアルガッタイヘイ、よろしく！
Release confirmed! Yay! Peace, everyone, please look forward to it!
こちらのグッズが販売決定です！
These goods are officially confirmed for sale!
と、いうわけで詳細を見ていきましょう。ドン！
So, let's take a look at the details. Ta-da!
はい、まず一つ目は「回転アクリルスタンド」！イラストはNardack先生に描いていただきました！うわ！
Right, first up is the 'Rotating Acrylic Stand'! The illustration was drawn by Nardack-sensei! Wow!
こちらですね、あの、こ、こういうことです。あの、あの、裏表になって…言いたい。裏表になってる。そう、あの、必ずいしょうと、この新しい新衣装で裏表になってます。
So this is, um, like this. Um, it's... front and back... I mean, it's double-sided. Yes, um, it features her regular outfit and this new outfit on the front and back.
クルクル回せるので、あの、座布団のことも回して遊んでください。よろしくお願いいたします。
You can spin it around, so please have fun spinning the zabuton too. Thank you very much.
そして、次がこちら！はい、「温感湯呑み」！
And next is this! Yes, the 'Thermo-sensitive Teacup'!
これ、さっきサンプルが、控え室に届いて試しました。あの、ちゃんとあったかいの入れると、ふゎってですね、ちゃんとぽこべが浮かび出て、座布団が打ち合わせとかね、あの、リハやってる間に湯が冷めきってちゃんと緑に戻り戻っておりました。
As for this, a sample arrived in the dressing room earlier and I tried it out. When you pour hot water into it, Pokobe appears, and the zabuton... well, during rehearsals, the water cooled down and it successfully returned to green!
こちらもすごく可愛くて、お寿司屋さんとかにあるサイズなのかな？結構大きめの、ちゃんといた湯呑みです。ぜひね、使ってもらえたら嬉しいです。
This is also super cute, it's about the size you'd find at a sushi restaurant, right? It's a fairly large, proper teacup. I'd be so happy if you could use it!
はい、そして次がこちら！はい、風真いろは 新、こちらポップダンス衣装って名前なんですけどのぬいぐるみです！
Yes, and next is this! Yes, the plushie of Kazama Iroha in her new 'Pop Dance Outfit'!
ぜひお迎えしてほしいな、風真さんのぬいぐるみでみんな遊んでくれ！っていうこと
I really want you to take one home, everyone please play with Kazama-san's plushie! That sort of thing.
で、このツインテールのね、新衣装、なんとぬいぐるみになりました！あの、手持ちじゃなくて、こう、こういうタイプだったかな？だと思うので、ぜひね、みんなのおうちに飾ってもらえたら嬉しいです。
And this twin-tailed new outfit has somehow become a plushie! Um, not holding anything, but like this type, I think, so I'd be so happy if you could display it in your homes!
そして次は、こちら！はい、なんと！風真のこれ、これとお揃いのこれがでます！これと、お揃いのネックレスが出ます！
And next is this! Yes, unbelievably! This necklace that matches Kazama's comes out! This matching necklace!
はい。で、普段ね、アクセサリーとか付けない大変にね、付けないよっていう方も、まあ、よかったら、こちらね、あのさっきのぬいぐるみに入って、一緒にセットにして飾っていただいたりとか、イベントの時に付けてきてもらえたら嬉しいです。おしゃれです。風真と一緒にお揃いに良かったらしよう。
Yes. And for those of you who normally don't wear accessories, well, if you'd like, you can set it with the plushie or wear it to events! It's fashionable. If you'd like, let's match with Kazama.
というわけで、そしてフルセットがこんな感じ！うわあ、なんだか爽やかですね。そう、ライブタイトルの通りリバースブルーなので、色々ちょっと、斑点斑点がついてたりします。
And so, the full set looks like this! Wow, it feels so refreshing. Yes, just like the live title 'Reversible', it has various speckles and patterns.
そして、購入特典はこちら！この戦争を終わらせに来ました！今回はですね、グッズが2種類出るということで、数量限定はせずに、ちょっと変わった特典にしてみました！こちらは裏表のタロットカードがついてきます！
And the purchase bonus is this! We've come to end this war! Since two types of goods are coming out this time, without making it quantity-limited, we tried making it a slightly different bonus! It comes with double-sided tarot cards!
楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいです。
I'd be so happy if you enjoy it.
数量限定とかではないので、ゆっくりね、あの、購入していたければと思います。
It's not quantity-limited, so please take your time purchasing it.
販売開始時間がこの後21時なんですけど、
Sales start at 21:00 shortly, but
ちょっと生配信の関係上、ちょっと生配信伸びる可能性のが今大なので、
due to the live stream schedule, there's a big chance the stream might run long, so
生配信中にみなさん、あの、買って見に行ってください。
please go buy and check it out during the live stream.
あ、でも、あの、数量限定とかないないので、安心してください。
Ah, but don't worry, there's no quantity limit.
はい、そして、フルセットの特典もうひとつあります。こちらです。
Right, and there's another bonus for the full set. Here it is.
はい、みんな大好きホロカのカードが1枚付いてきます！
Yes, everyone's favorite Holoca card comes with it!
はい、みなさんよかったらお手に取って、ホロカ勢のみなさんは使ってくださいね。
Right, everyone please pick it up and use it if you're into Holoca.
遊び方とか、あとカードの詳細はホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームの公式ホームページにてご確…ご確認ください！
For how to play and card details, please check the official Hololive Official Card Game website!
よし、今台本めっちゃ見た。言えなかったらやばいと思って。
Alright, I checked the script hard. Thought it'd be bad if I couldn't say it.
そして、こちら一緒にこの入れさせていただくカードは日本語版のみとなっておりますので、ご承知ください。
And please note that the cards included here are in Japanese only.
はい、カートのオープンですが、こちらですね、100万人記念グッズと誕生日記念グッズ、両方同時なので、みなさんよろしくお願いします。
Right, the cart opens for both the 1M milestone merch and birthday merch simultaneously, so please look forward to it.
ちょっとごめんなさい、生配信押してごめんね。ホロメンも配信を押してすみません！
Sorry for running over the schedule. Sorry to the holomembers whose streams got delayed too!
はい、というわけで、ちょっとお水飲みます。
Alright, so, I'm going to drink some water.
はい、というわけで、あと最後のお知らせとしまして、
Alright, so as one last announcement,
このあと本編終了次第ちょっとまた時間がね、確定じゃ15分からか20分からかどっちかなると思うんですけど、
after the main part ends, the time will probably be around 15 or 20 minutes later,
風真いろはのメンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブがございますので、
we will have a Kazama Iroha membership-exclusive encore live,
みんなが見たかったあの曲やこの曲を歌ったり踊ったりしますので、よかったら見に来てください。
so if you'd like, please come see us sing and dance to those songs you wanted to see.
よろしくお願いします！メンバーシップギフトとか今日から入ってくださったたいしさんもありがとうございます。
Thank you very much! Thank you to Taishi-san and others who joined via membership gifts today.
はい。そしてなんと残念なことに、次の曲が、みなさん、このライブ最後の曲となります。
And unfortunately, the next song will be the final song of this live, everyone.
え、みなさん、もう最後は何を歌うか、ある程度予想されている方も多いかと思いますが、
Uh, everyone, I think many of you might already have some idea of what the final song will be, but
改めまして、この度は風真いろは生誕ライブ2025にお越しくださいまして本当にありがとうございました。
once again, thank you very much for coming to Kazama Iroha's Birthday Live 2025.
そして、あの、制作のために一生懸命頑張ってくださったスタッフさんやダンスの先生やマネージャーさんや、皆さん、本当にクリエイターの皆さんもありがとうございました。
And to the staff, dance teachers, managers, and all the creators who worked so hard for the production, thank you very much.
あの、正直、いろいろあった昨年の年末から、ここまで声が戻ってライブができるっていうことがほぼ奇跡。
Honestly, after everything since the end of last year, being able to get my voice back and hold a live is almost a miracle.
なんだったら、もう半分諦めかけかけていたんですけども、スタッフの皆さんや、ファンのタイシさんたちがすごく支えてくださって、いろんな方に支えられて本日実施することができました。本当にありがとうございました。
In fact, I had almost given up halfway, but the staff and fans like Taishi-san supported me so much, and supported by many people, we were able to hold this today. Thank you truly.
正直、まだまだ本調じじゃない部分が多いのは正直なところです。
Honestly, there are still many parts that aren't in top shape.
だけど、今日少しでもこのライブを見て、たくさんの人に元気が1人でも多く届いていればなと思っております。
However, I hope that seeing this live today brought energy to as many people as possible, even if just a little.
これからもリハビリしながらですが、精一杯頑張ってまいりますので、皆さんこれからもよろしくお願いします！
I'll continue doing my rehab while giving it my all, so everyone, please keep supporting me!
はい、というわけで、最後の曲にふさわしいこの曲、皆さん最後に聞いてください。風真いろは新オリジナル曲「君にしか読めない手紙」。
Right, so, please listen to this final song fitting for the end. Kazama Iroha's new original song, "A Letter Only You Can Read".
ありがとう 書くとしたら
If I were to write "thank you,"
毎日になっちゃうくらい
it would become an everyday thing,
重すぎる 私の想いは
my feelings are just too heavy.
最後に伝えるね
I'll tell you at the very end.
君にしか読めない手紙
A letter only you can read
拝啓 私を
Dear you,
形作った君へ
who shaped who I am,
相も変わらず言葉を
I continue to send my words
届け続けています
just the same as always.
拝啓 未来で
Dear you, waiting for me in the future,
私待ってる君へ
waiting for me there,
響く音に憂いなどなく
are you spending your days
お過ごしでしょうか
with no sorrow in the echoing sounds?
不安が無い日なんて 多分無かったけど
Days without any anxiety probably didn't exist, but
私の言葉 君の言葉 重なって笑えたんだ
my words and your words overlapped, and we were able to smile.
ありがとう 書くとしたら
If I were to write "thank you,"
毎日になっちゃうくらい
it would become an everyday thing,
重すぎる 私の想いは
my feelings are just too heavy.
重すぎる私の想いは
These feelings, weighing on my heart,
最後に伝えるね
I'll save them for the final page.
君がいるそれだけでさ
That you are here—that that alone
理由になるなんて奇跡
could be my reason, is a miracle.
ありがとう足りないの
"Thank you" isn't nearly enough,
誤魔化すよ
so I'll stumble through with...
愛してる
"I love you."
魔法石のブレスレット
A bracelet made of magic stones,
シロツメクサの女王様
the queen of all the white-clover thrones,
プラスチックだらけの宝石箱で
a treasure chest of plastic gems,
永遠に遊べるよ君と
with you, I could have played forever.
思い出の欠片たち
With all these shattered memories
溢れるこの場所で
overflowing in this special place,
私の言葉 君の言葉
I want my words and your words to meet,
重ねて笑っていたい
so we can laugh together, face to face.
忘れられる世界で今
In a world where everything can be forgotten,
私が選んだ生き方
this is the way of life I chose.
手紙をさ 書いたからさ
And so I've written down this letter
この音に乗せて
to send it on this melody's flow.
ありがとう 書くとしたら
If I tried to write down all my thanks,
毎日になっちゃうくらい
I'd be writing every single day,
重すぎる私の想いは
these feelings weighing on my heart,
最後に伝えるね
I'll save them for the final page.
君がいるそれだけでさ
That you are here—that that alone
理由になるなんて奇跡
could be my reason, is a miracle.
ありがとう 足りないの
"Thank you" isn't nearly enough,
誤魔化すよ
so I'll stumble through with...
愛してる
"I love you."
ありがとうございました
Thank you very much!